If you ever deploy the infrastructure manually, you know the feeling.
You click a few buttons and your Kubernetes clusters starts running.
But later on, if you try to repeat the same deployment,
you missed a couple of things here and there.
Infrastructure as a Code exists exactly to prevent that.
Let's see how we can use Terraform to deploy the
clusters and resources into Google Cloud.
For this,
I assume that you already have VS Code installed and in
that you have already added Terraform.
If you're not aware of it,
you simply go down to Google, and it is straightforward to install the VS Code,
and similarly it is straightforward to install Terraform.
Lastly,
I also assume that you have Google SDK also installed on your local machine.
Now I'm using the MacBook,
but this exercise can be easily done on a Windows machine as well.
Now in Terraform, we should have one file, main.tf.
This is to initialize the Terraform configuration.
I start defining by the Google provider.
Then, I'm enabling the required APIs,
and we are creating the VPC network and subnet through this specific code.
Now on similar lines,
I have the variables.tf that contains a couple of
variables where I have given the name, the project ID,
region,
and our network name and our subnetwork name as a variable. And we
have outputs.tf where we have defined the output,
network name,
subnetwork self‑link. And lastly, we have
terraform.tfvars where I'm providing the project ID where
I'm going to exactly create all of these.
It's time to go and run that.
So first thing which we need to do is Google Cloud authentication.
So here in the terminal,
I'm typing gcloud auth application‑default login and say Enter.
This will redirect, and I'll do the Google authentication.
Now, once the authentication has been done, I'm going to run terraform init.
That will initialize.
Then I'm going to run terraform plan. That will give me the
exact plan what you're going to create.
And then finally I'm going to say terraform apply.
Now this is the point where it goes and actually starts
deploying our resources into the Google Cloud.
Now you can see that it has successfully created our resources.
Now I go down to my Google Cloud, go down to my specific project, that is hpc1,
and inside that, if I go down to my VPC there,
so you can see that I got it, demo‑vpc‑1. And if I go inside the demo‑vpc‑1,
I should be able to see the subnet as well, that is demo‑subnet‑1.
So that's how our Terraform has created the resource into the Google Cloud.
On similar lines, we can also use the CFT.
CFT stands for Google Cloud Foundation Toolkit.
They are the already approved templates from Google which you can
use to create your Infrastructure as a Code.
For example, in this, I'm using the CFT network module from the CFT,
which is an approved module for creating the network resources.
So instead of writing your own code,
you can use the pre‑built templates from the Google CFT, and
you can use that for creating your resources.